Efremov Alexey

Software developer: (lexich121@gmail.com (in) alexeyefremov (lexich





Summary

I'm an enthusiastic and self-motivated programmer from Tver, Russia. I have over 14 years of professional experience in software development and over 9 years working in the web area. I love to automate routine work and accelerate my productivity. Also, I'm an active member of the Open Source community and speaker at <u>language</u> tver.io meetups. In my mind, the best developer should improve himself and learn new things every day. On every new project, I also work on the Developer Experience of the project and its quality, and it helps to bring new features guicker and more predictable.

Work Experience

• **Hoodies** - *Software Developer* - January 2020 - Present (1 year 10 months) Projects:

metaplex.com - service of branded NFT storefronts

- created caching graphql gateway to speed up API responses
- new frontend for storefront generator

<u>republic.co</u> - investing platform

- o created frontend architecture (react, typescript, mobx, apollo) from scratch and migrated to it from Rails
- involved Graphql to project
- improved development experience with my own project
 - webpack-lazy-dev-server
- implemented Server Side Rendering
- **Revjet** *Software Developer* October 2016 January 2020 (3 year 1 month) Worked on Ads cloud tools with rich functionality. revjet.com React + typescript, ExtJS + Javascript, NodeJS
 - migrated application from javascript and ext.js to typescript and react
 - speeded up web-editor of creative ads
 - prevented memory leaks and crashing of browser pages
- Antorica Frontend Developer February 2015 October 2016 (1 year 9 months) Frontend part in travel startup <u>travel246.com</u> Ember.js, React, Javascript, Sass, NodeJS, Gulp, Webpack, unit and integrations testing, markup

- Salt & Pepper Frontend Developer September 2013 February 2015 (1 year 6 months) Creation variety digital projects and integration frontend tooling into team's infrastructure: Backbone, Coffeescript, Javascript, Sass, Css, pug, html, NodeJS, Gulp, Grunt, Yeoman
- JSC RPA RusBITech Senior programmer August 2011 September 2013 (2 years 2 months)
 REST service for medical project: Java EE, Java SE, oracle, C++, Qt Random process simulation: C++, Qt Economic simulation: C++, Qt, qScript Web-development: Python, Django, javascript, html, css, less Frontend development for medical project: Coffeescript, Javascript, Nodejs
- CPS Software Middle programmer July 2008 August 2011 (3 years 2 months)
 Graphic controls development for GUI library IML using in Tactics trainer for Russian
 Navy: C++, boost, Qt, ATL
- CPS Software Junior programmer February 2007 October 2007 (9 months)
 Development of a system of economic accounting. Java SE, Hibernate, PostgreSQL

Education

- Doctor of Technology, Automation Engineer Technology/Technician, 2011 2014 (Tver State Technical University)
- Bachelor of Commerce (B.Com.), Accounting and Finance, 2009 2013 (Tver State Technical University)
- Master of Technology (M.Tech.), Automation Engineer Technology/Technician, 2009 -2011 * Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Automation (Tver State Technical University)
- Engineer Technology/Technician, 2005 2009 (Tver State Technical University)

Skills

Typescript = NodeJS = React = mobx = redux = Graphql = webpack